<protocol name="wayfire_window_list">
    <interface name="zwf_window_manager_v1" version="1">
        <description summary="List and control opened apps">
            The purpose of this protocol is to enable the creation of taskbars
            and docks by providing them with a list of opened applications and
            letting them request certain actions on them, like maximizing, etc.

            Each created window has a list of outputs it is visible on.
        </description>

        <event name="window_created">
            <arg name="window" type="new_id" interface="zwf_window_v1"/>
        </event>

        <request name="destroy" type="destructor"/>
    </interface>

    <interface name="zwf_window_v1" version="1">
        <description summary="An opened window">
            A zwf_window_v1 object represents an opened window.
            Each app may have multiple opened windows.
        </description>

        <event name="title">
            <description summary="Title change">
                This event is emitted whenever the title of the window changes
                and immediately after the creation of the zwf_window_v1
            </description>
            <arg name="title" type="string"/>
        </event>

        <event name="app_id">
            <description summary="App-id change">
                This event is emitted whenever the app-id of the window changes
                or after it is created (the initial title)
            </description>
            <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
        </event>

        <event name="enter_output">
            <description summary="Window entered an output">
                This event is emitted whenever the window becomes visible on
                the given output. A window may be visible on multiple outputs.

                The output is identified by its name, which is identical to the
                name in xdg-output
            </description>
            <arg name="output" type="string"/>
        </event>

        <event name="leave_output">
            <description summary="Window left an output">
                This event is emitted whenever the window stops being visible on
                the given output. It is guaranteed that an entered-output event
                with the same output has been emitted before this event.

                The output is identified by its name, which is identical to the
                name in xdg-output
            </description>
            <arg name="output" type="string"/>
        </event>

        <request name="focus">
            <description summary="Request focus">
                Request that the current window is focused. However, there is no guarantee
                the window will be actually focused.
            </description>
        </request>

        <request name="minimize">
            <description summary="Request the window be minimized">
                Request that the window is minimized. No guarantee the window will actually be
                minimized.
            </description>
        </request>

        <event name="destroyed">
            <description summary="Window has been destroyed">
                This event means the window has been destroyed. It is guaranteed there won't be
                any more events for this zwf_window_v1. The client must not send any requests
                after this either.
            </description>
        </event>

        <request name="destroy" type="destructor"/>
    </interface>
</protocol>
